Guide to the C: A Journal of Poetry Archive ca. 1955-1966 (Bulk 1964-1966). MSS.008
Fales Library and Special Collections
C: A Journal of Poetry Archive
ca. 1955-1966 (Bulk 1964-1966)
1964-1966
Fales Library and Special Collections
C: A Journal of Poetry
MSS.008
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box.
The C: A Journal of Poetry Archive is a collection of correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the editor, Ted Berrigan. The collection also includes issues of C: A Journal of Poetry.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Content Note
The C: A Journal of Poetry Archive contains correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the editor, Ted Berrigan. Collection highlights include correspondence and manuscripts written by John Ashbery, Marianne Moore, and James Schuyler. The collection also includes issues of the magazine.
Arrangement
The C: A Journal of Poetry Archive is arranged alphabetically. Published materials in the collection such as issues of the magazine and comics are arranged chronologically.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence, Manuscripts, Covers, and Publications
Series II: Comics
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
American poetry -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Cover Art.; Postcards.; Small presses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Periodicals.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Literature, Experimental |x Periodicals.; Manuscripts for publication.; Ashbery, John, 1927-; Berrigan, Ted; Koch, Kenneth, 1925-2002; Guest, Barbara; Saroyan, William, 1908-1981; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Whalen, Philip; Schuyler, James
- Series I: Correspondence, Manuscripts, Covers, and Publications
  Scope and Contents note
  The C: A Journal of Poetry Archive is a collection of correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the editor, Ted Berrigan. Collection highlights include letters and manuscripts written by John Ashbery, Marianne Moore, James Schuyler and William Saroyan.
  - Correspondence and manuscripts - "A-L" including materials by John Ashbery, Barbara Guest, Kenneth Koch, and Joseph Le Sueur., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts - Marianne Moore., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts - William Saroyan., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts - James Schuyler., undated; 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts - Philip Whalen., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Covers, also contains an article on Joe Brainard's art., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Volume 1, Number 7, [February 1964] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 9, [Summer 1964] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Volume 1, Number 10, [February 1965] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Volume 2, Number 11, [Summer 1965] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Volume 2, Number 13, [May 1966] (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Comics
  Consists of one folder containing 2 issues of a comic book put out by many of the same people who contributed to C: A Journal of Poetry.
  - C: Comics, Nos. 1 and 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)